

PERSONAL DETAILS

Name: Clive T Matsinde

Gender: Male

D.O.B: 13 May 1988

Status: Single

Nationality: Zimbabwean

Religion: Christian

Address: **S21 Spain cluster, Apartment 103.**

CONTACT DETAILS

Contact Number: +971545153389

E-mail Address:

matsindect@gmail.com

Website:

www.matsindect.com

AREAS OF EXPERTISE

Programming
Languages: JavaScript
JSP, J2EE, C, C++, C#,
Visual Basic 6, Visual
Basic, .NET, HTML, CSS,
JavaScript, PHP 4.0/5,
XML, Python, Java, Perl,
Database: MySQL 4.0/5,
MS SQL 2008/2012, MS
Access, SQL, ProstgreSQL,
SQLite,

Full Stack Developer

PERSONAL SUMMARY

A highly resourceful, innovative, and competent Full Stack Developer with extensive experience in the layout, design and coding of software systems and web applications. Possessing considerable knowledge of the development lifecycle, programming languages and database management systems (DBMS). Experienced in developing applications, e-commerce websites and solutions for a wide range of corporate, charity and public sector clients and having the enthusiasm and ambition to complete projects to the highest standard

WORK EXPERIENCE

Full Stack Developer - WIDA, UAE (Oct 2018 - present)

Key Responsibilities:

- Develop and maintain current and new web-based applications with HTML5, CSS, JQuery, Angular.js, vue.js, (or similar Java Script technologies) front end and server side technologies.
- Develop other dynamic web application in .NET, PHP, Python and Java and API integration.
- Contribute to application improvement & optimization (through code audits, refactoring, caching, architecture changes)
- Handle server-side CSS pre-processing platforms such as LESS and SASS, asynchronous request handling, partial page updates, and AJAX, XML, JSON, Sharepoint, Wordpress; modern authorization mechanisms, such as JSON Web Token.
- Support the ongoing refinement of development & frontend methodologies and Implementing UI/UX, modern design concepts and customer journey, cross-browser, cross-platform & cross-device compatibility standards and behaviors.
- Participate in weekly and quarterly sprint planning & provide estimates on all tasks, wireless, switches, printers, copiers, mobile devices, etc.

Freelance Web Developer – Nicmart Business Solutions (Oct 2016 – Oct 2018)

 Worked with 7+ organizations from around the world, developing websites that include e-commerce, Networking: TCP/IP, LAN, FTP, DNS, DHCP, IIS, Active Directory, CCTV, Oracle, PL/SQL

PERSONAL SKILLS

- Excellent interpersonal communication
- Organization, and time management skills
- Customer focused dedication to effective service
- Leadership/manageme nt skills

ACADEMIC QUALIFICATIONS

BSc (Hons) Information Technology Chinhoyi University of Technology 2011 - 2015

GCE Advanced level Anderson Adventist High School 2006 - 2007

REFERENCES – Available on request.

- booking, portfolio, blog and multilingual functionalities.
- Increased traffic and enhanced page ranking by improving website structure, performing Search Engine Optimization (SEO) and Search Engine Marketing (SEM) for local improvements.
- Developed UI/UX strategies that include wireframes and mockups and for small and medium-sized enterprises.

Web Developer – Nicmart Business Solutions (July 2014 – Oct 2016)

- Building PHP websites using PHP based frameworks like codeIgniter.
- Planning and conducting cross-browser usability testing against W3C.
- Developing advanced database driven websites & systems including e-commerce.
- Back end development and maintenance of websites using PHP and MySQL.
- Developing compatible User Interface functionality using jQuery & other libraries.
- Developing web sites using MySQL, PHP, ASP.NET, JavaScript, AngularJS & other programming tools.
- Working in a data analyst role and with business intelligence applications.

ADDITIONAL EXPERIENCE

Web Developer -Aicsol Solutions, Zimbabwe (Jan 2012 – March 2013)